welcome to the stola the stoah is a
digital campfire where we go here and
dialogue about what matters most at the
night's edge what's happening now
[Music]
begin hello everybody and welcome to the
stoah the Stowe is a digital campfire
where we go here and dialogue about what
matters most at the knife's edge of
what's happening now my name is Raven
and I'm your host for the evening so
we're gonna begin with an interview with
Ayla and Hrothgar who are the founders
of a game that we've been playing with
here
a Scholl and so what we're gonna do is a
Q&A with with me and Ayla and Hrothgar
and then we'll move after 20 minutes to
the audience questions so if you have a
question that comes up while we are
doing our interview you can go ahead and
put it in the chat and during the
question and answer period I will
facilitate the questions so today we
have a line Hrothgar would you all like
to speak to us about what is a school
tell us about this game that's caused a
game of questions basically question is
designed after a whole bunch of research
to figure out what is most likely to be
divisive to generate the most
conversation and also filtered by ones
that we personally like - that's a
general summary so I'm guessing probably
all of you have played it has anybody
not played it here probably quite a few
people have it yeah so like there's
there's a couple different versions
there's the like physical version that I
have which looks like this it comes in
this lovely little box and it has like
so many questions in here like there's
just hundreds how many questions are
there 125 125 questions and they come in
different categories do you want to talk
about the different categories of the
questions yeah so there if I can
remember them there is a generic
personal question set there's romantic
controversial and taboo intellectual and
philosophical and sex and romance and
those categories came up after I would
have these questions on the floor and
Hrothgar helped also is like just kind
of naturally bidding them into whatever
it seemed right and we tried this like
multiple times and these same bins kept
emerging of like these sorts of
categories
we said I said yeah they said - yeah so
can you so you said that this is like
the culmination this of years of you
experimenting with with these questions
can you talk about like the very early
days like proto a school before it was
even conceived as a game where did this
the where did the kernel of this idea
begin yeah some Twitter polls I don't
know if you follow me on Twitter but I'm
like a really obsessive Twitter puller
I've tweeted I don't know maybe fifteen
hundred polls at this point which I have
recorded in the spreadsheet over the
course of maybe since maybe four years I
think so I would just obsessively write
down these questions and get responses
and then I would start to go to parties
and then realize actually it might be
good if I could bring some of these
questions than a party so I would start
writing these questions down and
eventually this transitioned into like
having little pieces of paper cut out
with the questions on them and so I just
had this stack she was really big stack
at this point I was like 500 questions
we ended up chiseling it down a lot for
a school and that was just like carry
them around to parties all the time and
then eventually people started to saying
I would buy this like if you were
selling this as a product I would buy it
and then I got me thinking and then then
I was hanging with Hrothgar for a while
and then Hrothgar was like he really
loved it he's like you know I am down
for helping make this a reality so yeah
so why did you need questions and why
did you start doing asking Twitter polls
in the first place why did you need
questions to go to parties with what's
the deal any beers they drink beers
[Laughter]
people just go to parties and then
they're like what are what are what are
we doing now you go and you you find
someone and then you talk to them for
what purpose what are you doing like are
you trying to like most efficiently find
someone who you want to like be your
best friend if so you should like know
what your goal is and then optimize the
amount of questions to learn that so
like my approach to parties is like very
like how do we max
is the enjoyment and like the kind of
connection I want to find from this
party is my personal goal I think
Hrothgar might have a slightly different
do you want George say something say
your relationship to this mm-hmm well I
really like I really like the concept
from the first time is that I thought
and I was around when Africa was in the
testing phase were like printed on or
like handwritten on cards and brought
the party students
I just saw the effect that had on people
I think a really well-crafted question
is like the antidote to having a strong
opinion about something we're really
good questions can crack people open
nicking they can illuminate the places
where we we've assumed thing and then in
the context of a party for some kind of
social space where people are already
sharing and discovering each other and
it just seems like a really powerful
tool yeah I also feel like and maybe
this is a weird quirky like rationality
thing but people like not answering
questions like where are you from you
know and just being like no I'm not
going to answer that question I want to
have more interesting engaging
conversation with people that isn't
based around like your job or like where
you live or like these very basic facts
about who you are but rather getting
into the your you're like opinions and
belief and like controversy and intimacy
and I think that this game also reminds
me of hot seat
which was something that we played in
the Seattle rationality kind of Golden
Age do you want to talk about like the
rationality community and its connection
to this game yeah for I don't I don't
know what is the familiar any people
have with the rationality community
let's assume low okay so the rationality
communities a bunch of people who read a
set of blogs is kind of how it started
like less wrong or
it's been slayed sir codex stuff like
that and and then meet up and then have
like specific kinds of conversations
with like certain standards of
communication which I find extremely
appealing it's like very clear and we're
like actually here to understand what
the other person means not to have this
like weird little war with words where
we're trying to prove our point so I
really really value that and they also
have like a bunch of like norms around
we're also going to have the most
efficient conversations possible and so
like a lot of the like original question
testing was deadly and in the
rationality community yeah and there's a
kind of idea there of intimacy hacking
could you talk a little bit about that I
actually don't know specifically with
that term refers to okay yeah so I
always thought it I thought of it as
being in relationship to the game like
hot seat where like basically you you
all agree on some sort of structure or
some sort of game that puts everyone in
position of being extremely vulnerable
to to the group and to being honest and
you know personal answering personal
questions and I see that this game also
kind of has that effect right because
you're you're really digging into what
is like juicy there's like controversial
questions both political sexual you know
there's questions about faith and all
sorts of taboos and that really digs
into parts of social interaction that
are typically in the shadows so I don't
know if you I have this belief that
everybody actually wants to be asked
these questions
I go to people say they won't and it's
not a norm in social circles but like
it's this really deep perspective of the
world that I think that people want to
be prodded in like the most terrifying
and uncomfortable places like what are
we doing if if not like searching for
the thing that hasn't been seen yet
mm-hmm
so can you talk about some of your
favorite questions and maybe some of
your least favorite questions in the
game Hrothgar you want to go first yeah
remember
so broadly my I think my favorite
category is the sad category maybe I
just like being sad but
I don't know if they're in order I don't
know if I can recall the stupid
questions but in what ways don't you
trust yourself in what ways are you yeah
I'm lifting also one pick him up with
that made it a game that's why I
remember them anyway that's this one
yeah so I like to collect them have you
been loved enough yeah
so that battle category has a flavor
that I really like and when I'm
brainstorming somehow I tend towards
that category favorite I don't know if I
could say least favorite these are the
125 that's like that questions out of
like it's over a thousand so or
something
Halon what about you what are some of
the questions that pop up pop out for
you right I think my favorite so the one
that I end up pulling out like from
memory whenever I'm in a group but I
don't have my deck with me is like what
how does it face out like what opinion
do you hold is the most controversial
among your peers or something I feel
like that tells you so much about a
person and like such a fast way and it's
like not too scary that people will like
put up too many walls like compared to
some of the other ones and it's like
personal enough that it really gets you
to know something about them that's my
go-to actually I have more answer so I
really like the question which of your
habits conflicts with your values and I
also really like the question is
bestiality wrong are you a vegan it's on
the same card and I think it looking
over there was just brilliant yeah well
that one I think actually didn't you do
that one as a Twitter cool yeah how did
that go
well I've tweeted a few times over the
years I usually will tweet things about
once a year to see like change every
time
yeah people don't like it people don't
don't really like their eating meat
being equated to bestiality if I could
press a button and then have it all of
the meat-eaters instead switch to being
bestiality people I would do that
that's also a technique that you use so
yeah let's turn to kind of a technique
that you use in some of these questions
or some of the different kinds of
questions that like the form essentially
of like pressing a button that's
something that you use what do you think
about like why do you use that as it as
a tool for yeah it's neutral because
there's like a lot of ways in which the
answers to a question will change a lot
depending on like the very specifics of
the framing and I've tried this before
with series of Twitter polls right I'll
ask the same essential question but I
will change like very minor details
around it like do you have to press a
button or do you have to walk across the
street and like push someone over like
you know but but the outcome is the same
and it's so I try and have like a stable
neutral middle ground that I use for
most of the questions to try and keep it
like kind of even and then that is the
button press think is like a button
pressing it is an action that you have
to do it's not like a nikkie negation
act for like a lack of action as in like
you don't have you have to actually
perform an action but it's also
extremely minimal so that that
combination is my favorite are there
other techniques that you use yeah
there's the the demon child series so
like behind one door there's a demon is
about to like do something horrible and
over here a child is about to die and
you can only like save the child or you
can go and stop the demon but not both
so that's another one that I really like
that you can like push a whole bunch of
things into that series like what is the
worth of a child really there's also a
series of like distant so I tested like
a distance question so how far away from
a child do you have to be before you are
morally obligated to save its life and
like the percentage of people who will
answer yes you are morally obligated to
save the child's life like increases the
closer you get to the child and
decreases the farther away you get
interesting so what is this revealing to
you about people what does this tell you
about how how we think about things and
like how groups work or how people
approach different moral questions do
you have any grand cakes on that yeah I
think that people have some sort of like
system of operation that they use and
it's extremely complicated and it relies
on a whole bunch of like tiny little
rules that are like conditional and
other things but this is subconscious
right like you don't have you can't
write a book about like the rules of
which you operate and instead we use
like labels which we stick on to our
extremely complicated operating systems
as like a general approximation of what
we do and so the thing that I'm really
interested in is we're revealing the
separation between like the actually
extremely complex system and the labels
so we'll say yes this is moral but then
if we like tweak it we can see the ways
in which that like peels off away from
the way we actually operate I think this
is fine this makes sense like like we
have to sort of have simplistic rules of
operation if we're going to describe
what we're doing because it's impossible
to actually describe the kind of rules
were operating on yeah hrothgar do you
have any anything to add to that um I
really really I really enjoyed that
description I'm not sure I have anything
out immediately so um cool
how did you so how did you like parse
down this deck so like popular demand
like effective use in games once that
you found to be your favorites how did
you get from a thousand to 125 we did
the system together Hrothgar and I I had
a huge spreadsheet list and then we went
down we've ranked it right we each went
down and put our own number like on a
scale from 1 to 7 and then we weighted
our own rankings pretty high and then we
had I think what 20 friends or something
go through and rate all of the questions
themselves and
questions were already selected from the
top most commented or liked retweet
commented on Twitter as well as the ones
that you can't really tweet the ones
that are open-ended as opposed to closed
so we had that that filtration system
initially and then we had a ranking
system and then we went through and
after we like averaged all the scores we
manually sort of tweaked some things we
liked and didn't like and also took the
top 25 questions from each category so
we had to categorize each of all of
those questions which there are a lot of
them and then then we took the top 25
from each category the Sun right do I
miss anything Hrothgar sounds great
it was really fun putting this together
I remember your parents also ranking the
question and we forgot yeah it really
matters the specific phrasing really
matters for how people end up
interpreting the thing yeah so there's
they're examples of questions I don't
know if I have an example right now
where if you phrase it one way just in a
conversation the conversation will die
and then phrase slightly differently it
generates a huge lively discussion so
cool does tune into that yeah that's
super interesting do you have like a
working hypothesis as to like why that
that happens or what kinds of like
asking what questions versus like who
questions or any anything like that it
just seems like that's a theme that the
framing like the specific ways that the
question is being asked like engenders
either possibility or it closes off
possibility so one very general rule is
that yes-or-no questions tend to be more
dead-end than other kinds of questions
and it's usually possible to reframe
yes-or-no question and a more open way
that's the one one thing that comes to
mind there's also questions that are
good to listen to so this was one
criteria that like we had to figure out
over time that you can't just ask
questions which people love to answer
you have to
ask questions that people love to listen
to other people answer is so much more
important and that will cause an actual
conversation because some people like
really want to hear what's going on or
is there's a lot of questions out there
that are so much fun to just answer
yourself but will kill any sort of
momentum collectively and so we did have
to like pry out some of those questions
from from the deck because we really
liked them but they just aren't good for
groups yeah that makes a lot of sense
that's that's really interesting yeah
there's definitely lots of questions
that for yourself that would be great
but for other people because you're
almost questions like bring out stories
and people and bring out like novelty
like you may I mean I found myself
answering questions in this deck and not
knowing my answer beforehand and there's
something kind of that puts you on your
edge when you are in front of people
especially answering a question that you
don't have a working hypothesis for
you're just freeform that's cool yeah
that's that's one more thing is we try
to include only questions that people
wouldn't have cached answers for that's
really important and specifically it's
even better to have questions where
every time you hear the question your
answer is going to be different so if
you if you if you develop an answer at
one time it's not going to hold for the
next time you get a question that's not
true for all of them but we aspire great
and I guess just before we move to the
question and answer period with the
audience can you tell us what's next for
a school is there anything on the
horizon yes school over to you want to
give us a little juicy secret about
what's coming well it's just a school
number two it's just another 125
questions yeah but we are still in the
process of selecting questions right now
we have a very large list same deal
so if anybody is interested in going
down and ranking how much you like
questions we are always looking for more
people to do that so that would be great
can they contact you through
cool yeah asshole they just just asked
me out and down to write questions and
then we'll give you a spreadsheet and
then you just put your name in and then
you just like put in how my ever nine
numbers you feel like putting in yeah
there's also a web version of the game
on the website which is what we're going
to be using in the following hour where
we're gonna play a school and I totally
recommend it to everyone
there's also a feature where you you can
actually submit a question and in the
website right yeah so if you have a
question that you'd like to see included
you can also include it on the website
so Peter I hear that you have a question
would you like to meet yourself and ask
yes I do have a question
so simply like who would you like to see
play a school and I was thinking of
someone who has stature and author maybe
an intellectual that you respect any
spaces I'm thinking like Robin Hanson
and Justin Murphy like those type of
people I'd like to see play so I'm
curious
but what who would you like to see play
this game play it like like if I want
publicity for the game that's a
different answer if I'm like I actually
don't know how they would answer a lot
of these questions and that's also
different I think I'd probably person
had the least ability to predict which I
would have to think about that I
couldn't just tell you also Rock gotta
feel free to jump in if you have any
it's a good question I will have to
think about it the when you ask the
question the first thing that popped
into my mind with the Pope just because
it's nice it's a good answer that would
be hilarious
okay so David Mack Nick would you like
to ask your question I would you know I
love your Twitter polls you remind me a
lot of Robyn Nance and I wish I had your
courage to ask these questions and just
take the heat from all the people that
are just bounded to turn to misinterpret
or hear another project their own
insecurities
sacred cows on you but my question is
are 30 questions that you really like
but you didn't include an asshole
because they are too outside the Overton
Window even for you there's this one
question which is like too far
rosco do you know the one I'm thinking
of no it's just more shock value there's
like questions that are more like force
you to consider really horrific things I
can think of one yeah but in regards to
non shock value questions no I put
literally everything in there that I
thought had any sort of thing like I
don't think we held back at all but
there's definitely some really like
gross out horror ones category for them
that's cold might be the right place
great thank you David so Travis would
you like to ask your question yeah I
hope it's not too windy over here so
what role did your experiments with acid
play in the development of the questions
and did a majority of the questions come
during trips
soon after trips or during periods of
like relative abstinence and is there
any correlation between like the
mind-altering properties of the drug and
the types of questions that you ask I
like that question so rasca I had an
idea to actually make a deck called the
acid deck and it's for reading the
questions while you are tripping and we
do actually have a plan to do this it's
probably going to be like maybe after
another deck or two but
but acid questions though the questions
that you come up with on acid that are
really meaningful for you on acid or not
like easily generalizable to people who
are not on acid so I don't know if how
many here have like an experience but a
lot of it's like like what are you
afraid of it's like a very general
question it might not generate great
conversation but it would be a great
rabbit-hole to start thinking of so no
acid didn't really give me these
questions
yes it gave me a lot of different
questions which were really useful but
not great for parties but the general
philosophy right of like question
everything like if there is a thing that
you haven't looked at like go look at it
and like figure out I think there's a
lot more skill in figuring out the right
question to ask for yourself then there
is to answer it like if you can figure
out the question to ask then you have a
direction to move and and if you don't
know the question to ask what you're
full of answers and then you're stagnant
so I think like that philosophy of like
the question is the movement and not
necessarily the answer it really like
lends itself to the philosophy pascoal
excellent thank you it's a great
question
Michele do you want to unmute yourself
and make your suggestion
sure hi I'm so fascinated by this idea
that you were talking about around there
are questions that people themselves
really love to answer but that other
people don't like hearing them answer so
I just love to hear some examples of
that I've heard people talking about
their own dreams is something for
example that people really love to talk
about but others hate to listen to I'm
wondering what the questions examples
are other examples yeah so things that
don't have good narrative arcs are one
so anything that has to do with like
facts about your life so I need sort of
exposition so like what is your favorite
X or where did you live when X so
sort of think people can really it feels
like meaningful to your identity be like
yes that time I lived in Paris right
like I am a person that lived in Paris
but like nobody gives a shit because
it's not a part of like a meaningful
narrative arc so like a lot of those
sorts of things like what's the most
interesting thing that you ever did when
you were a teenager like 10th tech
people tend to zone out when it comes to
stuff like that also things that are
slow introspection so things that are
like where are you in your life what are
you looking for and I mean I think you
can do it well if you are extremely
careful about the phrasing but there's a
lot of like man I don't know if I really
should be going for this job promotion
that that other people just aren't it's
not like exciting to hear you like
weighing a whole bunch of like tiny
options that are relevant to you and no
one else so things that are like either
like - zoomed in or - zoomed out tend to
sort of just pass on by other people
thank you so much s ting thank you
Miriam would you like to share your
question yeah see you had a thousand
questions boil it down to 150 but
clearly they're like these are
rank-ordered that's how you narrowed it
down 250 in the first place so what
we're like the top two or three that
just really get the party going do you
remember list of winners for we can
probably pull up the spreadsheet we have
it somewhere yeah I was about to
actually pull it up and we can get if
you could really say that if you don't
pull it up really fast but I think
they're all sad the sad questions
dominated the lead interesting why do
you think that is if it bleeds it leads
yeah I think I think it's the kind of
connection the people maybe are most
hurting for is like to be seeing their
pain and like a lot of other things are
fun but I think like
the connection in the pain is like the
thing it's like the most important thing
and I think that's why the sad one cool
how's it going North guard I all my
bandwidth is being taken up by this
dummkopf it might it might be yes well
we will just keep on going with the
questions in the chat and if you find
the spreadsheet will circle back to that
so we have a question oh oh no oh you
really chopping shit i'm trying again
how about now that's better yeah okay so
the top questions that we had are what
emotion are you currently suppressing or
ignoring what was the most significant
thing you've ever changed your mind
about and what ways don't you trust
yourself in what ways are you inhibited
from expressing love and what experience
the difficult SAR painful would you
recommend to everyone those are the top
five that's awesome thank you I got a
really popular question here in the chat
from Daniel Daniel would you like to ask
this question sure so one thing I've
noticed with really curious people is
that they tend to be very cerebral not
all the time but a lot of intellectually
curious people spend a lot of time in
the realm of the abstract and so I'm
always curious about how do you ask
questions in such a way or what sort of
questions get cerebral intellectual
types to speak more from their body as
opposed to from their head a
million-dollar question isn't it if I
knew the answer to that I would be
extremely happy
but so so I don't think we've optimized
for that super strongly in the deck but
I I know what you're talking about
there's like questions that bring you
back to the level sensation so there's a
couple questions that say like away from
your conscious response in the gut how
do you feel about X and so that's one
technique another is to avoid cache
responses like we mentioned earlier like
if you're really smart probably you've
thought about all the things before and
to like be able to throw someone off
like to put them in their mind into a
spot but that hasn't been before usually
that can be a little bit more genuine I
don't think those answers are really
that excellent because I think the
problem is a very hard one no easy
answers Daniel Philip
look would you like to ask your question
yeah sure hey guys so my thought is
since you spent a lot of time thinking
about the taxonomy of questions and like
different properties that questions can
have do you find yourself noticing the
types of questions that different people
ask or like you put people into like
categories or bins based on like oh like
this type of person like ask me these
types of questions all the time yes
maybe not like quite as like categorizes
as maybe I would hope but I think I
mainly noticed like the the frequency of
questions to answers that people give
that's like the number one maybe even
like outside of the question realm just
in general the thing I pay attention to
people is like how much time do they
spend like inquiring versus like
providing the answer to I think that
tells you a huge amount about a person
in regardless like types of questions
there's obviously the dichotomy of like
very simple where are you from versus
something that's unusual but beyond like
those two spectrums I can't say that I
like actually have a better developed
model for that but you record yeah I'm
now just thinking about the ways that
one could
my questions at all I think for me
there's some there's some measure of the
depth of a question of how far down it
seems to reach into just experience
itself so some questions definitely feel
more like surface level just like what
is what is this concept referring to or
something and then some questions feel
really really deep and maybe there's a
thing where people tend to be and tend
to be of a certain level of depth in
their inquiry about something that's the
first thing that came to mind okay we
have a question from and John sorry if
I'm mispronouncing your name would you
like to ask your question yeah my
question is 'm i'm wondering have you
noticed in your own life any changes and
the type of questions you ask
i'm having done this whole process yeah
i'm more easily bored at this point i
don't really ask many of the ask whole
questions anymore cuz i've asked them so
many times i i'm shifting slowly towards
trying to ask questions from like my
physical body as opposed to like my mind
like I'm becoming more curious about
like the way that it feels to be in the
presence of another person and asking
questions that try to like let me feel
that more clearly as opposed to like how
do we like analyze you know where our
philosophical positions lie although I
do still like doing that quite a lot but
that definitely has been the shift away
from like a sort of an analytical thing
more and towards a like a sensational
thing what about you Hrothgar I would
agree with that I think similar about
the being with the I'm more able to in
to it appropriate question in different
contact and and there's something about
viewing a question of the tool and then
being able to sort of just come up with
the right tool for that for the job and
that's really cool because I think I
almost want there to be a science of
inquiry I think it's it's potentially
really important of what what are
questions what are they doing what what
happens in the moment that you hear a
question what is it doing and then if
you've ever played this game maybe it's
just called questions where it's like an
improv game where you're only allowed to
respond with a question back and forth
so taking that really seriously is is
cool it results in a different state of
mind if you if you take it seriously
you're asking genuine questions yeah
definitely I that feels really alive for
me like the science of inquiry what is a
question doing and how come people can
feel so offended just by a question I
think that's yeah a li you probably have
a lot more to say about that than I do
on the shock side of that yeah yeah just
by pausing a question like in some cases
you know I see people respond to your to
your polls and they're like how could
she even ask this question you're like
what's wrong with that what's wrong with
even posing a question to the world they
they're so provocative they have the
possibility of being so enlivening for
people and it's it's it's it's just a
question mark at the end of it I guess
it's more than that it's more than that
yeah this is a huge thing I don't know
how many of you are up on the Twitter
thing but there have been several times
where the Twitter mob has like brigaded
me horribly four days of hate for ask
for Lily just a question like I think I
asked a question about bestiality a
couple of months ago just like what how
did we evolve out of liking animals
or something nothing we did like where
did that come from that that was a
mistake
Greg would you like to unmute yourself
and ask a question yeah I actually wrote
my question just before Hrothgar said
the phrase science live in Korea so that
was kind of a funny lead-in and I'm just
gonna read what I wrote out light it
seems like you're informally doing
social psychology research in a sense
have you studied any social psychology
or other academic research either to
help you interpret your findings or just
out of curiosity to see how what you've
observed compares to the science okay I
I started doing this originally excited
it was originally doing porn and I had a
large following of people who are
masturbating to me and I was like
they're gonna do things I say I can ask
them questions so I like way back in the
day started doing surveys on all of
these men and eventually found that I
had a whole bunch of data that I didn't
know what to do with and then eventually
found a friend to help like teach me
some statistics and like what P values
were and stuff like that so I'm not like
incredible at it but I have like some
basic knowledge but that's the entirety
of my education okay great
first principles we have two people
raising hands which is not something
that usually happens but Cara do you
want to tell us about your hand raising
I was talking to the point about why
people might get offended by a question
and just in general from my own gut
check when you ask a question it says
more about you than it does about how
like how like the response does about
the person who's responding so like how
you're framing the question is a social
code it's social signal to
another person that indicates your own
boundaries and that sometimes you can
cross a person boundary by asking a
question I mean often you can cross a
person social boundary just by existing
so I think that it really is just a
difference and how people have been
raised some people were raised to never
ask questions that will be seen and not
heard thing mm-hmm
and I don't have access to chat so I
couldn't I see yeah that explains it
well Thank You Ella
do you have anything to say in response
to that I mean that seems right like I
think the people that get upset at the
questions are you doing it because
they're like interpreting it as like a
threat in some way that like they are
pattern-matching like this series of
words on to other people who have used
those as war in the past which makes
sense so I think you're totally right
about that car great and then we have
Miriam would you like to ask your
question yes so I'm talking about this
willingness to even answer a question
this whole asshole game reminds me of
the work of Johnson Hite who
investigated universal moral foundations
and they would go around asking very
uncomfortable questions and then
cataloging the types of responses but in
this case it seems like we could open up
a new area of research to catalogue
who's even willing to answer and what
personality characteristics guide that
behavior I think this is like like a new
sphere of in Korea so not a question
yeah I think that's interesting I think
that a lot of people will answer the
question without answering the question
so you can even get people to like
engage but if you just pay attention you
realize they're not actually giving an
answer and I think like that that
probably is really indicative of
something you're right
great and we have a question from Rachel
hi so I could offend it at one of your
tweets and then I read your response
I just became a huge fan of community um
that associates with us heretics you
know and that's more involved in like a
harder rationalist analytical side of
things
um how are you treated by the the more
mainstream women in the sex worker
community not well not well at all
I have been blacklisted from a lot of
sex worker groups because they think
that I am a racist
oh and homophobe like oh you know all
the words that people say when they're
mad at you yeah so and generally not
well at all
I think I like I have some sort of like
animosity towards them in response for
that like like I'm mad that sex workers
aren't more open-minded like you should
be open-minded you're a sex worker but
it doesn't seem to be the case
great thank you and let's see what else
we got here do you mind um if we pull a
question from the deck and you answer it
you have a category of preference
sure can we just randomize y'all I like
random is this and then maybe you tell
me when I close my eyes
okay they're mixed up a little box for
mine smart yeah tiny box is a little too
tiny okay here we go
question number 86 do you believe the
set of concepts like duty should
obligation and deserving or ultimately
more valid or meaningless meaningless
they're like like an incomplete term you
know how sometimes you have terms I'm
gonna try to make this short I can feel
myself strategy to talk a lot but like
but I was religious I believe in these
words that seemed real like like a
theological words like the hypostatic
Union for example and this was very real
to me and then once I left the faith I
realized that it was a word that
actually wasn't attached to anything but
it was useful in the context and I so I
think like moral duty etc is are also a
set of concepts that are like useful
into the sort of religious framework of
morality but like ultimately don't
actually mean anything it's just wind
yeah okay
wait can you repeat the question -
totally do you believe the set of
concepts like duty should obligation and
deserving are ultimately more valid or
meaningless hmm so I I I guess I'll take
the other positions just so we have an
interesting contrast I think there's a
sense in which those concepts are
referring to something that's very real
and it might not be real in the way that
is originally understood so certainly if
there's a should or a duty or an
obligation it's it's a self thing so
when I have should its very self as a
force that's like pushing or pulling me
towards something probably because I'm
afraid of what will happen if I if it
doesn't go the way
should says it should but then we get
into a territory where we're talking
about sort of how how morality is based
in sensation or something rather than
like the the moral code who are you
satisfying God or something yeah
interesting any response Eila definitely
we've only got like about ten more
minutes
let's see if there's any really like
biting questions from the chat and if
not I will just pick another question
and we'll keep going oh we do have a
follow-up question to the sex worker
question grace would you like to ask
your question yeah like I'm wondering
how you made sense or how you make sense
of the other sex workers targeting me I
like how simple that question was I like
how like it was very concise and like
just the right night level of bake so
like I try and think of it as
demographic so it's like what makes sex
workers more likely or at least like the
same amount of likely maybe I'm just
more exposed to them and so I'm more
likely to experience pushback from any
group that I'm more exposed to so it's
possible that this is not unique to sex
workers at all but if it is then like my
theory read the chat thing is that like
sex workers tend to like require like
more intense social signaling in some
way or like more intensive in group
circling because like they're subject to
accept pressures and they also seem to
be like really liberal and I don't I
don't really have anything against
liberalism in general but there's like a
kind of brand of liberal that feels very
like identity driven and very
performative and it seems to me that
like the sex workers I think
countered tend to be more in that
direction like they tend to be more
performative Lee liberal which might
make sense because it get aligns with
the sort of the ideology of sex work
which I am very Pro obviously so I'm not
so so me making sense of it is usually
just trying to think of like what are
the reasons for why it happens to be
like this selection seems to not like me
yeah can I just follow up on that yeah
of course so I understand you're trying
to make sense of why they're targeting
you is that what I'm hearing I think so
and so I'm wondering have you made any
sense from it you you understand what
does you understand of why they do it so
I mean there's a there's like a slightly
different question between why do people
get upset at me in general and it's a
slightly different answer than why are
sex workers tending to get mad at me and
it's possible that those two answers
overlay a lot so like for example people
get upset at me is because they
interpret my questions as meaning a
thing that they don't for example and
it's possible this is the explanation
that explains why sex workers don't like
me also like 90% of it does this answer
what you're saying or is a different
thing yeah what I'm hearing is you
trying to make sense of it you're trying
to help me understand your sense making
of it that there isn't that there is a
black and white binary announcer here
that's correct okay thank you great
thank you for that question grace and
let's see here is there anything that
you all really want to share with us
about a school like things that you've
you've come to understand by endeavoring
on this process I mean anything that
comes to mind this would be a great time
to share that silence non-starter wrong
phrasing
I hit that sweet middle grounds I know
it's too broad um yeah I've only played
it a couple times usually on the the
Socratic speed-dating sessions but I've
always I've really enjoyed it when I
played it I think it brings out a side
of people that you don't usually see
mm-hmm and it's um it's like this fun
but more personal alternative to
something like cards against humanity'
which is just fun and silly kind of
thing this is more like let's cut into
the soul and see what comes out yeah I
enjoy I look forward to experiencing
more of it and I'm definitely looking
forward to asshole - yay you have some
fans here at the stoah no nice I'm
really thrilled to see so many people
who feel so like-minded to like what I'm
doing and all of you seem to be like
really down for the same sort of
approach and that's really heartwarming
great and okay so let's see here I'm
gonna ask you one more last question and
then we'll wrap up the session and we
will move on to actually playing a skull
which everybody is totally invited to
join us for this for the second hour a
second hour here how about this one on
Planet a everyone's 30% dumber and
you're a genius by comparison on Planet
B everyone's 30% smarter and you're an
idiot by comparison you stay the same
which planet would you prefer to live on
it's just horrible it's horrible to
think about
it's not fair to other people that we've
put this in the deck you go first
well I think about the answer yeah I
think I'd rather be an idiot and
I find that over time I try to surround
myself more and more with people who are
really smart and so planet whichever one
it was say or be the one where I'm an
idiot seems like a natural extension of
that and as long as like granted that I
can get over my own problems with
feeling stupid which seems possible then
that would be a great planet to be on
and also assuming that the people who
live there aren't apples which is not
another question yeah that's true
smartness and not being an asshole or
two different things
yeah it really feels like the trade-off
is between like can you handle the
emotional hit of being the stupidest for
I know if a world where everybody was
30% smarter sounds really great like
things will get fixed and run smoother
we'd have fewer problems so that's the
trade-off and I think I I think I want
to be the person that takes the stupid
being stupid and I don't know if I
actually am that person it's hard to
tell because I'm blinded by desire great
honest answer great okay well let us
begin wrapping up here thank you so much
a Lloyd Hrothgar this was amazing I've
been so excited to talk to you both
about this and I'm so glad we could make
it happen thank you for putting it on
really good at this and also very good
questions too yeah thank you and thank
you to the audience for all your
excellent questions and for engaging
with this conversation today and I
invite all of you to come play a school
um great so we're gonna um finish up
here with the recording before we do
Daniel would you like to talk about the
the event that's happening later on
today the dark stoah sure so we're
having a pretty intense session at the
dark stoah tonight which is his weekly
series being run by Pat Ryan who's the
most dangerous man on the Internet and
he's talking about the
pick of blackmail and I promise there
will be a very unnerving mic drop moment
at some point in tonight's event so if
you want to get mildly horrified then
sign up for that it's at at 8:30 Eastern
tonight yes so that'll be just right
after the game of basketball wonderful
and then next week here at the stove
we've got some really exciting names
we're gonna have Daniel schmock timber
ger here we're gonna have Benjamin boys
we're gonna have Joe brewer Christopher
life from one nation so stay tuned for
the events for next week and we'll just
say that the stoah operates on a gift
economy and if you feel inspired to give
us a gift you can visit us at the stoah
dot CA and also please
you can visit asshole at asshole dot io
and thank you all so much for being here
today thank you
alright Peter you can cut the recording